<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>JCR二区 on 王一珉</title>
        <link>https://wymin1996.github.io/categories/jcr%E4%BA%8C%E5%8C%BA/</link>
        <description>Recent content in JCR二区 on 王一珉</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <copyright>王一珉</copyright><atom:link href="https://wymin1996.github.io/categories/jcr%E4%BA%8C%E5%8C%BA/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Adaptive robust stability control of all-electrical tank gun compensated by radial basis neural network</title>
        <link>https://wymin1996.github.io/p/adaptive-robust-stability-control-of-all-electrical-tank-gun-compensated-by-radial-basis-neural-network/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://wymin1996.github.io/p/adaptive-robust-stability-control-of-all-electrical-tank-gun-compensated-by-radial-basis-neural-network/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;doi&#34;&gt;DOI
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1109/ACCESS.2023.3325339&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://doi.org/10.1109/ACCESS.2023.3325339&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;摘要&#34;&gt;摘要
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stability control of the tank gun has emerged as a pivotal issue for moving tank gun control systems (TGCS). As a complex electromechanical integrated system, TGCS of moving tank inevitably possesses significant parametric uncertainties and uncertain nonlinearities. To effectively enhance the stabilization control performance of TGCS, in this study, we introduce an adaptive robust control (ARC) strategy based on radial basis function neural network (RBFNN) compensation. The adaptive technique is employed to address the parametric uncertainties, while the RBFNN is constructed to approximate the uncertain nonlinearities and realize feedforward compensation. Subsequently, to suppress the residual uncertainties, a nonlinear robust feedback control rate is devised to strengthen the robustness of the developed controller. Lyapunov analysis shows that the proposed controller achieves uniform ultimate bounded stability. Extensive simulation and electromechanical experimental results confirm the effectiveness of the proposed controller, which shows outstanding performance in handling strong parametric uncertainties and uncertain nonlinearities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;关键词&#34;&gt;关键词
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;adaptive control, robust control, radial basis neural network, tank gun control system&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Nonlinear robust control of vehicle stabilization system with uncertainty based on neural network</title>
        <link>https://wymin1996.github.io/p/nonlinear-robust-control-of-vehicle-stabilization-system-with-uncertainty-based-on-neural-network/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://wymin1996.github.io/p/nonlinear-robust-control-of-vehicle-stabilization-system-with-uncertainty-based-on-neural-network/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;doi&#34;&gt;DOI
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/electronics13101988&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/electronics13101988&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;摘要&#34;&gt;摘要
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To effectively suppress the effects of uncertainties including unmodeled dynamics and external disturbances in the vehicle stabilization system, a nonlinear robust control strategy based on a multilayer neural network is proposed in this paper. First, the mechanical and electrical coupling dynamics model of the vehicle stabilization system, considering model uncertainty and actuator dynamics, is refined. Second, the lumped uncertainty of the vehicle stabilization system is estimated by a multi-layer neural network and compensated by feedforward control. The high robustness of the system is ensured by constructing the sliding mode feedback control law. The proposed control method overcomes the limitations of sliding mode technology and the neural network and is naturally applied to the vehicle stabilization system, avoiding the adverse effects of high-gain feedback. Based on Lyapunov theory, it is demonstrated that the proposed controller is able to achieve the desired stability tracking performance. Finally, the effectiveness of the proposed control strategy is verified by co-simulation and comparative experiments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;关键词&#34;&gt;关键词
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;vehicle stabilization system; sliding mode control; neural network; robust control; lumped uncertainty&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
